ANDREW TERRELL

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Sr. technology and economic analyst with ten years of experience in business, communications, diplomacy, economics, and public policy. Served over 140 organizations globally, including various US and UK government agencies. Proven success in finance, leadership, government affairs, innovation, operations, and project management. Keen eye for mitigating risk and relationship building. Mission-oriented, focused on delivering value, and a reliable anchor for any team. Values multicultural, interdisciplinary perspectives. National Security fellow (SAFE)

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Co-Founder, Sr Policy Consultant 2010 – 2021 TG Consulting – CA, DC, GA, MD, NC, NY, VA, EU, JP, UK

- Managed a boutique consultancy team of specialists focused on multidisciplinary international economic and technology projects.
- Provided policy guidance to DHS, CISA, OMB and GSA on critical technical issues around emerging technologies (e.g. Al, Data Gov, IoT, NLP, Quantum).
- Provided content, management, and strategic advice on the next iteration of the President's Management Agenda and Cross Agency Priority Goals.
- Produced detailed strategic reporting deliverables for decision makers, including budgetary, market intel, public policy, and macroeconomic analyses.
- Wrote articles and contributed to RFP responses on technical capabilities.
- Offered strategic recommendations for research methodologies and policies to mitigate perceived bias based on current political trends.
- Providing management, operations, and budgetary support to a wide variety of public policy, technology, and security-focused projects.

British Consul of Business & Government Affairs 2016 – 2020 British Embassy (HMG-FCO) - DC, GA, NC, SC, VA, UK

- Assisted in managing a \$1.7M project budget, \$200B in trade, and \$1T in FDI across diverse sectors (heavily AEM, life science, and tech).
- Providing subject matter expertise for technology companies focused on AI/ML product development.
- Assisted small businesses in financial management and accessing special UK and US business development programs.
- Managed intergovernmental teams on delivery of senior level public policy projects (e.g. defense, diversity, energy, environment, trade).
- Account managed critical relationships with over 250 business leaders and political stakeholders, supervising over 300K points of contact.
- Provided counsel to HM Ambassador, cabinet officials, policy leads, and embassy team on a wide array of federal and state affairs.

CONTACT

Phone: +1.828.238.7406

Email: [andrew].[terrell]@[me].[com]

EDUCATION

Master's, International Political Economy & Law, 2013

Warwick University — Coventry, UK

UK Russell Group Research Institution

Research Assistant, Econ Dept; Published in the Roo Institute's 10 Ideas in Econ

Development Journal; Departmental

Distinction Award; Tech Society, President

Bachelor's — International Relations,
Political Science, and Economics, 2010
Richmond American International
University (LSE Joint) - London, UK
Sr. Thesis Award; Student of the Year; U.S.-Japan Diplomatic Fellowship.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Served on the White House's National Economic Council, National Security Staff, and OSTP.
- Appointed to Her Majesty's Diplomatic Service.
- Consulted for OSD and members of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.
- Nat'l Security and Energy Fellow (SAFE).
- Supervised over \$400M in business development and trade accounts.
- Organized, hosted PM Cameron visit and various cabinet Ministers.
- Co-Founded two companies.
- Published researcher.
- Raised over \$25,000 for charities.
- Led UK D&I efforts.

Lead Intelligence Analyst (OSINT), Strategy & Product Dev 2014 – 2016 Cision, Bulletin Intelligence – DC, VA, EU, UK

- Produced customized intelligence reports and data analyses to C-suite executives and government agencies around the world, including the FBI, Treasury Department, and White House.
- Managed collaboration between global teams to develop new data products for improved risk management and decision-making.
- Directed implementation of new business intelligence tools, selecting appropriate solutions and aiding in corresponding processes.
- Evaluated consistency and importance of different business intelligence data to determine optimal delivery strategy.
- Mapped process activities to identify shortfalls and propose options to rectify operational inefficiencies.

Defense Policy & Financial Analyst 2013 – 2014 McAleese & Associates – DC, VA

- Advised aerospace companies, financial firms, and the Secretary of Defense (OSD) on budgetary, legal, policy, and technical matters.
- Provided economic and technical analysis of the impact on the defense industry base of DoD procurement decisions.
- Managed analysis of Congressional and agency budgets to model impact on acquisition, logistics, and technology capabilities.
- Produced daily deliverables, including real-time analysis on defense programs, contractor operations, mergers, and CIFIUS reviews.
- Generated reports of findings to help management with making key decisions. Senior Editor for all RFP responses.
- Used Excel to model data and forecast trends that consistently attracted new business.

National Economic Council Fellow 2012 – 2013 The White House - DC

- Analyzed qualitative and quantitative research to deliver economic and technology policy analysis to the NEC and President of the United States.
- Provided budgetary analysis and research to the finance, housing, national security, and technology policy teams (chiefly NSS and OSTP).
- Managed large sets of domestic and international macroeconomic data for the White House and several agencies.
- Produced daily briefings on crisis issues, including cyberthreats, the Eurocrisis, housing market, and at-risk international financial markets.
- Prepared policy briefing materials for major international summits, including Jackson Hole and the US delegation to the ITU.

SKILLS

- Budgetary analysis and management
- Business administration
- · Business analysis
- Business development
- · Cultural adaptability
- Cross-functional communication
- Data analysis, science
- · Economic analysis
- Financial analysis
- Financial management
- Fraud Analysis
- Multidisciplinary research
- Multi-purpose writing and editing
- Political analysis
- Project management
- Public policy development, research
- Public speaking
- Statistical Analysis
- Strategic planning
- Operational management
- Relationship management
- Research management
- Risk analysis
- Languages: English, native; Japanese, working proficiency (N3); Spanish, working proficiency.
- Technical skills: Bloomberg, C, CSS, Haver, HTML, JavaScript, LexisNexis, MS
 Office (inc. Excel), PHP, Python, R/RStudio, React, SQL, Tableau.

AFFLIATIONS

- American Economic Association
- British-American Business Council
- Kiwanis International
- National Economists Club
- The Royal Society
- U.S. Air Force Association
- White House Alumni Association
- Warwick Alumni Association
- Young Professionals in Foreign Policy